Guide to the Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera MSS.295
Fales Library and Special Collections
Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera
1798-2009
1850-1950
Fales Library and Special Collections
Smith, Andrew F., 1946-
MSS.295
20.75 linear feet in 45 manuscript boxes and 23 folders in 3 shared oversized boxes
Andrew F. Smith (born 1946) is a culinary and food consultant, historian, lecturer, and writer. The Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera, dating from 1798 to 2009 (bulk dates: 1850-1950), was collected to inform and support Smith's scholarship in the food studies field. The collection contains manuscripts and published materials including recipe booklets, food labels, food advertisements, clippings, circulars, and serials that document the promotional practices of early American culinary corporations and the consumer habits of average Americans during the mid-19th and early 20th centuries.
Separated Materials
Almanacs, periodicals, and items that documented unique social organizations or cultural groups were removed from the collection to be cataloged.
Arrangement
The Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera retains Smith's original arrangement in which items are alphabetically organized into files by corporation, individual author, or social organization name; by subject, such as coffee or tomato research; or by genre. Corporate names that are preceded by personal names are arranged under the first name or initial; for example, Joseph Campbell Company is listed under "Joseph," and H. J. Heinz is listed under "H." The container list includes bibliographic citations for many, but not all, items found in the collection.
Biographical Note
Andrew F. Smith (born 1946) is a culinary and food consultant, historian, lecturer, and writer. Smith was the editor-in-chief for the Oxford Companion to American Food and Drink and Savoring Gotham: A Food Lover's Companion to New York City; and is the author of many other titles including the three-volume Food in America. He serves as the editor for Reaktion Press's Edible series and teaches food studies courses at the New School University in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired from Andrew F. Smith in 2010, with an accretion donated in 2017. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2010.295 and 2018.118.
Scope and Contents
The Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera dates from 1798 to 2009 (bulk dates: 1850-1950) and contains materials used in support of Smith's professional contributions to American culinary history and food studies as a consultant, educator, and writer. This material served as a study collection on the history of the industrialization of the United States food system; in addition, Smith compiled the collection to facilitate research about the problems created by this industrial food system and its alternatives. These materials also served to illustrate connections between the cultural, economic, historical, social, and technological events that influenced American eating habits of the past and how they have shaped American eating habits of the present. To this end, materials were collected to aid study in the cultural dimensions of food, and the relationship between health and nutrition, as documented by the promotional practices of early corporate America.
Smith implemented a filing scheme that alphabetically organized items by corporation, individual author, or social organization name; by subject, such as coffee or tomato research; or by genre. Within the collection, corporate names that are preceded by personal names are arranged under the first name or initial; for example, Joseph Campbell Company is listed under "Joseph," and H. J. Heinz is listed under "H." This collection is dominated by cookery manuals and other food-related publications, including recipe booklets, circulars, and pamphlets. Many cookery manuals include more general information for the household in addition to recipes; for example, the assorted items produced by D. Ransom & Sons & Company of Buffalo, N.Y. include recipe booklets or illustrated encyclopedias with almanac-like instructional text such as astrological writing, calendars, medical advice, and statistical information. Publications that include instructional text speak to how the food industry conceived of and enforced socially acceptable behavior in terms of not only eating habits, but overall modern codes of conduct. Text of this nature appears within the collection not only in the form of commercially-released recipes, but also in early 20th century government publications such as bulletins and reports from the United States Department of Agriculture. It also appears in the publications of religious leaders, including those of Reverend William T. Findley. Other materials include promotional items such as a set of corporate stereoscopic photograph cards, which date between 1892 and 1905. While this collection is dominated by publications exclusively discussing the United States food system, the materials also include exploration of Mexican cuisine in the form of early 20th century Gebhardt Chili Powder Company recipes and The Prospects of a Banana Trade in Trinidad (1887), a pamphlet distributed by the Superintendent of the Royal Botanic Gardens of Trinidad.
The Andrew F. Smith Collection of Cookery Ephemera provides a comprehensive resource on mid-19th and early 20th century American advertising practices, documenting how food companies conceived of unique public, corporate identities through text and image, in the form of brochures, catalogs, flyers, grocery lists, newsletters, food labels, and souvenirs. In addition, these corporate identities are manifested in extended narratives that discuss company origin and or values, such as in the Eerie Preserving Company's A Book of Heraldry (1893); in photographic prints of factory grounds; and in postcards featuring the interior design of a restaurant. Materials also document corporate interaction with individuals in the form of financial records such as bills and subscription forms, and also documents individual reactions to corporate materials in the form of handwritten recipes or commercially released publications with evidence of personal use.
Advertisements.; Black-and-white photographs.; Brochures.; Clippings (information artifacts); Commercial correspondence; Cookbooks.; Cooking, American -- History -- 19th century.; Cooking, American -- History -- 20th century.; Cooking -- United States.; Financial records; Food habits -- United States.; Food industry and trade -- United States -- Societies, etc.; Food science and technology -- History.; Food writing.; Formulas, recipes, etc.; Manuscripts (document genre); Pamphlets.; Postcards.; Printed ephemera.; Recipes.; Scrapbooks.; Armour and Company.; Best Foods, Inc.; Borden Company.; Charles B. Knox Gelatine Co.; Church & Dwight Co; Culinary Arts Institute.; D. Ransom, Son & Co.; Fleischmann Company.; Gebhardt Chili Powder Company.; General Foods Corporation.; General Mills, Inc.; H.J. Heinz Company.; J.R. Watkins Medical Co.; Joseph Campbell Company (Camden, N.J.); Kellogg Company.; Kraft Foods Company.; Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.; Pillsbury Company.; Postum Company.; Procter & Gamble Company.; R.T. French Company.; Royal Baking Powder Company.; Rumford Chemical Works.; Standard Brands Incorporated.; United States. Department of Agriculture.
- Cookery Ephemera, 1798-2009
  - A1--International Steakburgers, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott Laboratories--Sucaryl Sweetener; Abram Cox Stove Company, circa 1906-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Content
    Abbott Laboratories. Watts, Sara Hervey. Low Calorie Gourmet Dining (the Sucaryl Way). Chicago, IL: Abbott Laboratories, 1961.
    Abbott Laboratories. Watts, Sara Hervey. Calorie-saving Recipes with Sucaryl. Chicago, IL: Abbott Laboratories, 1958.
    Abram Cox Stove Co. The Princess Novelty Cook Book. Place of publication unknown: Abram Cox Stove Co., circa 1906.
  - A. C. Legg Packing Company, Inc., circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adolph's, Ltd., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Adolph's. Best Beef Buys that You Can Now Barbecue, Broil and Oven Roast. Place of publication unknown: Adolph's, undated.
  - A. E. Edwards Company--Del-Nut Dessert, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A. F. Russell & Company, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agate Iron Ware, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Agate Iron Ware. The Agate Cook Book. Place of publication unknown: Agate Iron Ware, 1890.
  - The Aid Society of the First M. E. Church, circa 1850-1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The A. I. Root Company, circa 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Root Company. The Use of Honey in Cooking. Place of publication unknown: A. I. Root Company, undated.
  - The Akron Milling Company, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Akron Milling Company. Murrey, Thomas J. The AMC Perfect Cereals; What to Buy and How to Use Cereals. Akron, OH: Akron Milling Company, 1885.
  - The Alaska Freezer Company; Alaska Packers Association, circa 1900s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Alaska Freezer Company. Ices and Frozen Desserts. Winchester, MA: Alaska Freezer Co., circa 1900.
    Alaska Freezer Company. Good News for Ice Cream Lovers. Winchendon, MA: Alaska Freezer Company, undated.
    Alaska Freezer Company. Good News for Ice Cream Lovers. Winchester, MA: Alaska Freezer Company, circa 1900.
    Alaska Packers Association. Argo Red Salmon Cook Book; How to Eat Canned Salmon. San Francisco, CA: Alaska Packers Association, circa 1906.
  - The Albert Dickinson Company Pop Corn, 1900, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Albert Dickinson Company. Pop It Yourself. Minneapolis and Chicago: The Albert Dickinson Co., circa 1900.
    Dickinson. "Little Buster Hull-Less Pop Corn." Chicago, IL: The Albert Dickinson Co., 1921.
  - Alden Fruit-Preserving Company; The Alden Fruit Vinegar, circa 1872 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alka-Seltzer, circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Alka-Seltzer. The Daily Diet. Place of publication unknown: Alka-Seltzer, circa 1912.
  - Allen, Ann H., 1845 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Allen Dairy Maid, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Allen Dairy Maid. Cute Salad Tricks with Cling Peaches from California and Cottage Cheese. Place of publication unknown: Allen Dairy Maid, undated.
  - Allen, Elinor Genung, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allied Bazaar, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company, circa 1900-1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company. Top Stove Roasting and Steaming. New Kensington, PA & Oakland, CA: The Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company, undated.
    Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company. Canning Preserving and Jelly Making. New Kensington, PA: Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company, undated.
    Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company. Canning, Preserving & Jelly Making Made Easy Using a "Wear-Ever" Aluminum Canner and a "Wear-Ever" Preserving Kettle. New Kensington, PA: Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company, undated.
  - The A. M. Church Company, Ltd., circa 1850-1880s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Agriculturalist, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    American Agriculturalist. Cook Book. Ithaca, NY: American Agriculturalist, 1953.
  - American Bottlers of Carbonated Beverages, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    American Bottlers of Carbonated Beverages. Delightful Recipes with Carbonated Beverages. Washington, DC: American Bottlers of Carbonated Beverages, circa 1950.
  - The American Butter Institute; The National Creameries Association; The National Milk Producers Federation, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    American Butter Institute; The National Creameries Association; The National Milk Producers Federation. Recipes Royale Delicious Easy Ways to Use Quality Dairy Products. Chicago, IL: American Butter Institute; St. Paul, Minnesota: The National Creameries Association; Washington, DC: The National Milk Producers Federation, 1951.
  - American Can Company, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    American Can Company. Canned Fish Recipes. New York, NY: American Can Company, undated.
    American Can Company. Choice Recipes and Menus Using Canned Foods. New York, NY: American Can Company, undated.
    American Can Company. So You're on a Diet. New York, NY: American Can Company, undated.
    American Can Company. Young, Isabel N. The Story of Salmon. New York, NY: American Can Company, 1934.
  - The American Cereal Company, 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    American Cereal Co. America's Cereal Foods and How to Cook Them. Chicago, IL: American Cereal Co., 1894.
    American Cereal Co. America's Cereal Foods and How to Cook Them. Chicago, IL: American Cereal Co., 1893.
  - American Dairy Association, circa 1950-1970s (Box 1, Folder 26)
    American Dairy Association. Creative Cooking with Cottage Cheese. Chicago, IL: American Dairy Association, undated.
  - American Egg Board, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    American Egg Board. Always Eggs. All Ways. Park Ridge, IL: American Egg Board, 1974.
  - American Fruit Growers, Inc.; American Fruit Product Company, circa 1842, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    American Fruit Product Company. Superior Salad. Rochester, NY: American Fruit Product Company, undated.
    American Fruit Growers Co. Blue Goose Buying Guide: How to Get the Most for Your Market Money. Pittsburgh, PA: American Fruit Growers Inc., circa 1928.
  - The American Guernsey Cattle Club, circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    American Guernsey Cattle Club. Guernsey Productions; Milk, Cream, Butter, Cheese, Delicious, Nutritious, Efficient. Peterboro, NH: American Guernsey Cattle Club, undated.
  - American Heart Association; American Hominy Company, circa 1920-1940s, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    American Hominy Co. Selected Recipes for Cooking Hudnuts White Corn Products. Indianapolis, IN: American Hominy Co., undated.
  - American Honey Institute, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    American Honey Institute. It's a Honey. Madison, WI: American Honey Institute, undated.
    American Honey Institute. National Honey Week; Last Week of October. Madison, WI: American Honey Institute, undated.
    American Honey Institute. Honey Recipes for Sweets for Energy for Conservation. Madison, WI: American Honey Institute, 1942.
    American Honey Institute. Fortified with Honey. Madison, WI: American Honey Institute, undated.
  - American Ice Cream & Candy Ca.; American Institute of Baking, 1902-1906, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    American Ice Cream & Candy Ca. Advertising card. Merida, Yucatan: American Ice Cream & Candy Ca., undated.
    American Institute of Baking. Turn to Sandwiches. Chicago, IL: American Institute of Baking, 1957.
  - American-Journal Examiner, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    American-Journal Examiner. The Sunday American Cook Book by Mme. Tetrazzini Compiled by the Distinguished Opera Diva from Her Own Private Collection of Recipes which She has Gathered from Famous Cooks in all Parts of the World. New York: American-Journal Examiner, undated.
    American-Journal Examiner. The Thanks-giving Cook Book; A Collection of Choice Recipes by Monsieur A. Escoffier, of the Ritz-Carlton Hotels, the Greatest French Chef Special Supplement of the Sunday American. New York, NY: American-Journal Examiner, 1911.
  - American Legion Auxiliary; American Medical Association, circa 1920-1940s, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The American Livestock Breeds Company, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The American Molasses Company; American Motors Corporation, 1923-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    American Molasses Company. Forty Ways to Use Molasses–the Healthful Sweet. New York, NY: American Molasses Company, 1923.
    American Molasses Company. Grandma's Old Fashioned Molasses Recipes. New York, NY: The American Molasses of New York, 1936.
    American Motors Corporation. Tips on Home Freezing, How to Freeze Food, Package Food, Cook Frozen Food. Detroit, MI: American Motors Corporation, circa 1930.
  - American Novelty Company, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Pop Corn Company--Jolly Time, 1920s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    American Pop Corn Company. Having Fun with Popcorn. Sioux City, IA: American Pop Corn Company, undated. circa 1930s.
    American Pop Corn Company. "Speed'er Order Blank and Complete Price List, JOLLY TIME." Buffalo, NY: American Pop Corn Company, undated.
    American Pop Corn Company. "Popportunity." Buffalo, NY: American Pop Corn Company, 1929.
    American Pop Corn Company. "Advertising that Gets Results for Operators of Pop Corn Machines." Sioux City, IA: American Pop Corn Company, undated.
    American Pop Corn Company. The American Pop Corn Story and Recipe Collection. Sioux City, IA: American Pop Corn Company, undated.
    American Pop Corn Company. Favorite Ways to Serve Pop Corn. Sioux City, IA: American Pop Corn Co., circa 1920s.
    American Pop Corn Company. undated letter signed by Howard C. Smith, mentioning "Favorite Ways to Serve Pop Corn" brochure. Sioux City, IA: American Pop Corn Company, undated.
  - The American Rice Food and Manufacturing Company; American Spice Trade Association, circa 1900-1940s (Box 2, Folder 13)
    American Rice Food and Mfg. Co. A Cook Book Better Than Toys It's the Very Best Food. Matawan, NJ: American Rice Food and Mfg. Co., undated.
    American Spice Trade Association. The Heritage of Spices. New York, NY: American Spice Trade Association, undated.
  - The American Stove and Range Company; American Stove Company--Schneider & Trenkamp Company, 1909, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    American Stove Company. "Reliable" Cooking. New York, NY: Schneider & Trenkamp Co., a Division of American Stove Co., undated.
    American Stove and Range Co. Specialities for 1909. Keokuk, IA: American Stove and Range Co., 1909.
  - The American Weekly Household Almanac, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Americans Helping Americans; Amherst Woman's Club, 1910, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Americans Helping Americans. Appalachian Mountain Country Cookin' 1992. Mount Vernon, VA: Christian Relief Services, 1992.
  - Angelus-Campfire Company; Angelus Flour--Thompson Milling Company, circa 1900s-1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Angelus-Campfire Co. How Famous Chefs Use Marshmallows. Chicago, IL: Angelus-Campfire Co., 1930.
  - Armour and Company; Armour Packing Company, 1896-1923, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    Armour. Armour's Dry Sausage. Chicago, IL: Armour and Company, undated.
    Armour and Company. Farmer, Fannie Merritt. Pastry Wrinkles. Chicago, IL: Armour and Company, 1915.
    Armour. (card) "Soup Making a Pleasure with Armour's Extract." Chicago, IL: Armour & Co., 1896.
    Armour. 60 Ways to Serve Armour's Star "The Ham What Am. Chicago, IL: Armour Company, undated.
    Armour. Around the Clock with Armour Bacon: 8 Ideas for Better Eating. Place of publication unknown: publisher unknown,undated.
    Armour. Culinary Wrinkles or How to Use of Armour's Extract of Beef. Chicago, IL: Armour & Company, circa 1890.
    Armour. Pork Recipes Platters of Pork. Chicago, IL: Armour & Company, undated.
    Armour. Armour's Fresh Beef Cuts. Chicago, IL: Armour and Company, undated.
    Armour. My Favorite Recipes. Place of publication unknown: Armour Press, 1907.
    Armour. Palmer, Ida M. Culinary Wrinkles Practical Recipes for Using Armour's Extract of Beef. Chicago, IL: Armour Co., 1905.
    Armour Packing Co. "Neither Corned Beef nor Roast Beef, but Much More Delicious." Kansas City, MO: Armour Packing Co., undated.
  - Artwork, undated (Box Shared Fales 002, Folder 3)
  - A. Schilling & Company, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Schilling. Flavor Secrets A Schilling Product. San Francisco, CA: A. Schilling & Company, 1930.
  - Asgrow Pop Corn, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic Stamping Company, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Atlantic Stamping Company. Peaches and Cream; the Whole Year Round. Rochester, NY: Atlantic Stamping Company, circa 1919.
  - Auto Vacuum Freezer Company, Inc., circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Auto Vacuum Freezer Co. Neil, Marion Harris. Auto Vacuum Freezer Recipes. New York, NY: Auto Vacuum Freezer Co., Inc., circa 1910.
  - A. Williams & Company, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bailey & Bradley, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Bailey & Bradley. Family Recipe Book and Fund of Information. Coldwater, MI: Bailey & Bradley, 1902.
  - Baker Extract Company, circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Baker Extract Co. Baker's Pure Fruit Flavoring Extracts. Springfield, Boston, Portland, NY: Baker Extract Co., undated.
    Baker Extract Co. Some New Selected Recipes; Tested and Proved Good. Springfield, MA: Baker Extract Co., undated.
  - Ball Brothers Company, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Ball Brothers. Ball Blue Book of Canning and Preserving Recipes. Muncie, IN: Ball Brothers Company, 1943.
    Ball Brothers. Ball Blue Book of Canning and Preserving Recipes. Muncie, IN: Ball Brothers Company, undated. Edition K.
  - Banana Distributing Company; Banana Research, 1857-1961, circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Banana Distributing Co. Everyday Banana Recipes. New Orleans, LA: Banana Distributing Co., 1927.
    Banana Bunch. Bananas, Bananas a Food with Young Ideas. New York, NY: Banana Bunch, undated.
  - Barclay & Company, 1864-1872 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Battle Creek Food Company, 1920-1929 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    Battle Creek Food Co. Entrees for the Vegetarian Dinner. Battle Creek, MI: The Battle Creek Food Co., 1929.
    Battle Creek Food Co. The Art of Slenderizing. Battle Creek, MI: Battle Creek Food Co., undated.
    Battle Creek Foods. Battle Creek Foods and Vegetarian Recipes. Lowell, MA: T. A. Whelan Co., undated.
    Battle Creek Foods. Battle Creek Foods and Vegetarian Recipes. Cleveland, OH: The Chandler & Rudd Co., undated.
    Battle Creek Foods, distributed by Almar Stores Co. Battle Creek Foods and Vegetarian Recipes. Battle Creek, MI: Almar Stores Co., undated.
    Battle Creek Foods, distributed by Reid Brothers. Battle Creek Foods and Vegetarian Recipes. Staunton, VA: Reid Brothers, undated.
  - Bauerline, Inc., 1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Bauerline. Home Made Banana Recipes. New Orleans, LA: Bauerline, Inc., 1929.
    Bauerline. Yes, Home Made Banana Recipes. New Orleans, LA: Bauerline, Inc., 1929.
  - Bayoline Quinine Hair Tonic, circa 1875 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Bayoline. Valuable Family Receipts, Bayoline Quinine Hair Tonic. Boston, MA: Levi Tower, Jr., circa 1875.
  - Beech-Nut Packing Company, 1911-1924 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Beech-Nut. Happy Mishap. Canajoharie, NY: Beech-Nut Packing Co., 1911.
    Beech-Nut Packing Co. Beech-Nut Peanut Butter. Canajoharie, NY: Beech-Nut Packing Co., circa 1914.
    Beech-Nut Packing Co. Beech-Nut Peanut Butter with Some Views of the Home of Beech-Nut Products and the Fine Class of People who Put Them Up. Canajoharie, NY: Beech-Nut Packing Company, circa 1920s.
    Beech-Nut. Allen, Ida Bailey. The Beech-Nut Book of Menus & Recipes. Canajoharie, NY: Beech-Nut Packing Co., 1924.
  - Beef Industry Council; Belkin Corporation, circa 1990-2000s (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Beef Industry Council. Facts about Beef. Chicago, IL: Beef Industry Council, undated.
  - Bensdorp & Company Amsterdam, Dutch Cocoa & Chocolate Works, circa 1900s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Berdan & Company; Bernard Meyer, circa 1905 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Berdan & Company. The House of Berdan - a History, 1836 - 1902. Toledo, OH: The B.F. Wade Printing Co, circa 1905.
  - Berry, Lucinda Hollace, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Best Foods, Inc.--CPC International, Inc.; Richard Hellmann, Inc.--General Foods Corporation, 1927-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
    Best Foods. The Salad Bowl. New York, NY: Best Foods, Inc., 1928.
    Best Foods, Inc. The Salad Bowl. New York, NY: Best Foods, Inc., 1930.
    Hellmann. Salad-Ideas. Long Island City, NY: Richard Hellman, Inc., 1927.